and we should love to hear from and what
better if you just finding it you in
this town misdemeanor George Ford saw I
don't know if many of you know but
George's the CEO of Commodore AI they
just launched a amazing a product of
which I use personally so I'm a big fan
of George and Georgia is the people know
that he's the first person to Jailbreak
iOS and thanks to him we have you know
this capability huh he he will be
sharing his perspective of autonomy from
his vantage point and what common area
is doing and and you must have a part of
the product and out so I think they're
fun to make sure few quick points are
one thing that I want to highlight is
and it shows the enormous of this
problem that is that the trying to solve
so first of all the hardware range from
said and that's something that George is
trying to address right now if you build
a nice fancy car with my girls and all
you talking but 7250 killed your
daughter is doing it that you know maybe
like less than flu case you can have in
the garden which you fifty second point
is how many miles that we need so it
keeps increasing so twenty the right to
wear that twenty billion miles that we
have driven actually so what it means is
that the more data you have the more
accurate your model would be and that's
a chocolate that you need to solve and I
think how do you solve it at the
interchange format that is all vegan and
then I think the data is in a problem
that be generating tons of amount of
data from one terabyte
[Music]
these numbers keep changing but at the
end what we say is that a lot of data is
generated from these kinds of sensors
and that we have what problem are you
trying to solve so the problem we're
trying to solve is that 1.3 million
people that die in road accidents every
year $30,000 in North America and we
trying one of the business case or use
cases to make that completely you know
address that and then you get there and
then obviously that out of the problem
that suggestion and then the other areas
that we need to perform so but I think
that's abundantly the foundation and
then I would like to invite George to go
over his presentation and
[Music]
this whole space is insanely sad
there's don't listen to what is put out
by marketing people and my business
people that's all you're hearing from in
this space please look at it for
yourself how many of you have actually
gotten to ride in one of these cars
probably if you guys have experienced
what it's test autopilot
all right how many have written in a way
moment how many vary the test autopilot
today we go right you see what's real
and you see what's not real and this is
it this is it honestly it depresses me
so much you know why play a game if
everybody is playing by a different set
of completely rigged rules where you
know what does drew Carey say and shows
like it's all made up and the points
don't matter I mean that's what it seems
like
so my name is George Hotz I'm the
president of coming I in 2015 I rigged
up an acura to drive itself you know
I've never be one and like we wanted to
build a vision system thought about
those days my mobile I know like I could
use a few months that I did then you do
this and then you're like okay well this
will be easy right that you are on
autopilot this will be easy to sell to
the car makers right oh no no it's not
easy because the car makers I mean
finally now it has to stop
again sad there's a Paul Graham tweet
from five years ago saying the Model S
is the iPhone of cars of the difference
to the Model S the iPhone is when the
iPhone came out all the phone
manufacturers like oh well crap together
we go
catch up to that and all the carmaker's
laughs anyone else I kind of know what's
gonna buy an electric car all right look
what you are today so yeah we make this
thing this is only one is called comma
two it's 999 dollars you can put it in
your compatible Honda Toyota chief GM
Chrysler that supports 63 different cars
and it basically gives your car Tesla
autopilot equivalent functionality you
can drive for hours on the highway
without touching anything actually in
that way it's even better than autopilot
we use a public facing camera to monitor
the driver I was do it GM does this with
supercruise to this really there's three
good systems on the market today is
autopilot there's super cruise there's
us so maybe go to the next line this is
what this thing looks like mounted in
the car
it's our slogan is make driving chill
that's another thing people are always
like all self-driving cars our goal is
to reduce accidents or call the safety
no safety is a necessity thought it cold
right safety doesn't sell products what
what are you gonna do you hear Monica
right like this isn't know let's look at
is big driving champ safety is just an
added bonus right the purpose of cars is
not to be safe the purpose of course is
to get people from point A to point a
safety is just something you need to do
and need to have in your product so I
hate this rhetoric around it but again
you who comes off of all of us so we're
are completely open-source all the code
that runs on the air it's called open
pilot it's 100% open-source honestly you
can't get this stuff away you can't get
this type of way there are companies now
there are eight house companies now
trying old game is
they're trying to pitch to OEMs and
they're trying to pick something that's
worse than what we're literally giving
away for free with an MIT license this
thing is really good it's a thousand
bucks if you have a supportive car go
buy them and try like going in to search
for open pilot you'll find drives nobody
else again it's not a marketing material
these were users sitting at the wheel
watching the car drive for hours and
hours and hours so yeah we have on the
user things old we have over 1500
monthly active users and that's our
cumulative miles all the way home is 20
million miles you're 15 right like it's
it's not this nothing this is this is
nothing like I've shown you Tesla's
billions and billions of billions and
that's another great myth of this thing
I call twenty million miles it's so much
it's really nothing
this thing is just getting started we're
growing exponentially and you wanna
solve all the five economy that's how
you do it the only way to really do it
is with big data the incremental
improvements and with an end-to-end
solution when people are trying to break
things down into perception and planning
they already lost 0.15 negative comment
earlier from this target in the area and
announcement
I think the necks are all the time I
would say our good friend Alex Roy is
pizza podcast podcast which is a very
good podcast keep anonymous bait he
always say that in the levels of
autonomy only they even ever counts
because I love to I think we really saw
the problem of Keaney in the driver
alert on before and after car also for
commercial vehicles level 40 is the
first level you can't take the driver
out and see if you can accomplish a lot
of but you need not meant what by dreams
doe level 2 level 3 and level 5 probably
are not so much having a business value
level 3 as you may know is supposedly a
very fully or better economist but the
driver need to be engaged at full time
it is very difficult for the driver to
trust this vehicle and to keep alert but
at the same time so that really leads to
some safety concerns from from our
perspective and of a 5 is I think for
the completion of the for the levels
right you are asking this to be able to
drive a process that there no back
wheresoever you know anytime anywhere so
we believe that level 4 is the good use
case for trucking just given the
situation I have mentioned in the
parking space and level 2 is good for a
passenger car probably in the near
future to be implemented for for you and
I use it's a total myth that the levels
are different 2 3 4 & 5 are exactly the
same the only difference between the
miss was taking liability for level 2
the drivers homes liable and level 5 the
drivers never liable
this is made by business people it's not
made by engineers she could say this is
a level 2 system what
that mean it means that on its own it
makes more mistakes than a human would
but it's not a qualitative difference as
we drive mistakes down to zero
eventually one day well okay when does
it become level five when it's ten
percent safe of any human to X 1/4 10x
safer right it's just a question of how
many statements you have this whole
dichotomy of look if you're building a
system if you're building a level 2
system that detects the lanes on the
road you've already lost
pleasantly oh good for little white
marks they've lost all right the way
that we train this is completely untamed
we look at where humans dry to the
scenario what is the definition of
driving it's what humans do when they
dropped if you're thinking about a
limited operational domain you're never
gonna solve level 5 but you're not even
gonna build a good level 2 system so why
not solve the whole thing and then they
get you know quantitatively better over
time
there's no qualitative difference thank
you
next question is no you seem to get bit
in the
between senses to be used there the
whole night on camp everybody and there
is a visual sensing it's a test that is
permanent and it's been going on for a
while and nothing like a dot mentions
that the only car that actually is in
the road whether it's dead 2 to 5 we
call it our the testers so the question
to all of you would be that you feel
that Richard only sensing can be a
solution for solving these problems or
data is a monster I'll be fast
how many you could drive a car how many
you have a lidar I would say
pragmatically we gotta get rid of the
lidar but we use it down University
currently because it makes some things a
lot simpler so yeah
to symbol is also a vision based
solution our camper actually can be over
a thousand meters away which is quite
substantial especially for turkey you
have to longer stop with a search for
big rigs we do believe a camera based
initiative will be much stronger the
entire base solution just because of
that range of reception distance for a
best our system today your problem can
see around 200 meters but four cameras
can see much more them what I think the
combinations are really increasing
redundancy and bring out somewhere in a
stable system yeah it's just all about
redundancy and kind of giving the
impression to people that they are safe
I mean yes we do have dual ice and we
trust our eyes sometimes we take them
take our bikes off the road and instead
expect a partner to write itself but
leaving that aside I mean if I gave you
a car with just one camera people do
tend to get a little bit nervous so it's
probably more of a phase where we need
to tell you that no there's more than
one non sensor that's taking care of you
so it's all about no pun intended
perception but over time yes I do think
mission will I mean there's nothing grew
enough to communicate of us being safe
in our cars but it's just more of an
inherent missing
let's run and see more inputs to make
you feel much safer quick come in an
interception I want people to be scared
using these systems I don't want people
to feel safe because none of we're
better than humans people should be
scared and people should be ready to
take over at any time I thank you I'm
just curious if you think that 5g with
its low latency and high reliability is
important or a necessity for level 4
level 5 and if that's not the major
impediment what are the two or three
major amendments to the adoption of
level 4 5 thank you it's all completely
AI there's no difference at all between
40 and 5g Archie's mostly German my
height is IJ still nowhere near reliable
enough to have any cloud in the loop for
a level 4 dragon system I think you
leave me impression that all these
redundant sensors and cameras and
wonderful is working about a perception
of safety rather than actually required
for
a bit yep sorry I didn't mean to leave
that impression what we are saying what
I'm saying is that yes the technology
will get better and better over time
definitely it's it's software it's it's
science we can solve the vision problems
you can make it very very safe today you
know we hear many many potential
customers asking this question okay you
know what I'd like I mean I don't feel
very safe as a Tesla I mean this is an
encoding someone do you have a lighter
so that question comes up very often do
you have a rate of how many radars do
you have it's to take people's people
definitely feel safer when you have
multiple redundant sensors so we do have
to address that as well because we are
at the end of the day selling a vehicle
or leasing a vehicle to an end customer
people with one eye can drive cars very
safely when they do crash it's largely
because they're drunk distracted or
asleep not because their iPad thank you
so much I think you might give a big
hand
[Applause]
[Music]